So, my name is mark wilson thomas and I'm a program manager on the visual studio
id team I look off...visual studio editor but I'm part of the team that looks after all of
the core infrastructure that all the experiences inside visual studio live on so,
my piece about the edit
...you'll see several other pieces that we'll talk about today so I want to be the I think probably the seventh
person to welcome you to san francisco and to build...after the cams in the...xi
...enjoy them I'm hoping that ...justify the fact that I'm currently standing between you and your lunch.
By being here today to talk about the some great stuff that the team that
...parts of has been working on to make your experience
...studio twenty fifteen better app.
So, they made me put this slide in
early I just really want to emphasize that it's great to get your feedback and,
...valuations will really count and we do actually read every single one of them and
the tweak and untouched what we talk about as a result so what you say
mathis and upset?
Is our agenda for today and, the next hour we're going to be spending some time
looking at the changes we've been making in visual studio two thousand fifteen?
And, I'm going to be focusing particularly on things that we've done to help you
find and fix errors in your code...vicks issues in your code
will cover a whole bunch of stuff as well that is around how we've done that
in a way that is personalize to your needs and to the devices that you work
on and also takes into account the kinds of services that you have to work with in the world that
you're building apps and today so let's get started with that?
First up I
...talk a little bit about the visual studio product family in
two thousand fifteen so these are the new additions a visual studio that will be available in the
twenty fifteen timeframe I'm sure some of you've probably seen all of this
before it's been available for quite some time and in fact actually there's a
...at the bottom that you can refer to get more details but
what I really want to emphasize here is that we've been simplifying the choices that you have to make when you
decide which visual studio addition to use so if you're working in a
...enterprise environment and, you're looking for a free...to work with
...studio community is your answer okay and you probably all
a web justification all visual studio twenty fifteen community also supports extensions
so you can use all your favorite extensions from the via ecosystem with the product
...so you're no longer stuck with not being able to do that which you needs to be able to do in the express
skews.
We've simplified the full-page line-up of the professional an enterprise
...only two-page additions if you want to see what the differences
between those are I really do suggest you hit up that link there because enumerating them here would be very
dull so, it's importantly understand that the your
choices a simplified and you don't have to spend as much time scratching your head before you get started.
Talking of getting started one of the ways in which we've made visual studio
set of us as a place that is much more customized to your needs and
much more personalized your needs is we've started to really work on simplifying and customizing
...okay what you'll see when you install the release candidate which you
have access to today is a smaller default core set
of items...up...the default...visual studio working to make that
footprint smaller still and the idea there is if you don't work with sequel
server you don't work with cplus-plus you shouldn't have to pay the tax
...installing that on your disk and maintaining
going forward which means that we should actually have a good impact both in terms of your
own disk footprint but also in terms of the experience that you get when you update visual
studio as well so we don't have to take care of as many bits if you don't like them down in the first-place
what means is that there are more choices available say when you get to the optional
dialog if you're not finding the thing that you need present when you install
and ossie the story is that you would you need to go and
...it through the optional features dialogue we are thinking about some other possibilities there and,
we be interested...feedback of what kind of experience you might like for things that
...installed out-of-the-box but what we're putting forth now is if you want to find and it's not
instill by default...up the option options and,
you can do this in a change scenario as well throughout remove programs
we think it's better that you have a smaller cool long story short...supporting a whole lot
more platforms I think if you've been kind of staying awake in the connection I really have you have because I thought it
was pretty exciting one you'll notice...supposing a whole lot more platforms after the box them
...we have in previous versions of visual studio...and by that I mean
...a platforms that targeting so,
notably for instance we are now supporting android out-of-the-box that is not a small piece
of work and is actually something you don't want to opt into but those platforms
...broadest than they've ever been in the past however,
we still have kept our previous policy and kind of
pattern of being side-by-side compatible with previous versions of visual
studio so I want you guys to be afraid to go ahead and installed ossie ...are plenty
of caveats and comments on what you need to think about their but
in broad terms we are side-by-side compatible and we do test for that scenarios so you should be able to
stick this on your machine right alongside visual studio twenty thirteen for instance and have
no problems trying it out that's an important scenario for us we...make sure that we get all of your feedback and we
...that having to have a special machine is not necessarily the easiest way if
you to give that feedback there are other options if you're in an environment that's really not bound
all you have production machines...cautious in one way or another you can get hold of
as a virtual machines to but please do hit up the release candidate links to get the
full details on that but we are side-by-side compatible and as I alluded
to earlier we are working very hard to factor visual studio in such a way in terms of
...packaging to make sure that it is in units that can be updated more cleanly
and, more quickly what that means is you should experience when we...the
put out some new piece of tooling a lot of the time you're going to experience...much quicker update
...much smaller download for those visual studio updates so that's just something to watch out for when we
ship those first updates and as, you know, we're on this regular update cadence now and, that we hope
will make a big difference to...so you get a customized visual studio install experience?
...personalization that making of your visual
studio also extends to what we do with your settings
and services and this is where I'm going to help into some demos but first off I want to ask a quick show of
hands how many of you ever sign in visual studio losing that little box...top
...corner.
Probably about half just on a quick squid...the lights a real bright and
here but it it's not surprising to me that about half of you do and that's great but,
what I think you'll see in this next demo is that in twenty fifteen
...a whole lot more reasons why you want to sign in visual studio?
So, this is the release candidate build a visual studio twenty fifty and is the sign
...for those of you obviously...spotted before...the using
it that's fine I'm actually going to go ahead and sign in here and what I'm going to do is you can see
our previously been using a another can here but I'm going to use my?
Microsoft account and this is...work or school account to give
its proper name that's what the official term is but it's the
account I used to sign on work we've had for a lot of feedback from
various folks that it's very important for them not to have to have a
separate live id from the...that from the one the...to sign at
...you see here this is actually going to impose on me all of the same
security requirements that I would have we have to factor of
education at microsoft so I have to use a virtuous...
here and I'm going to sign on but I'm signing on here with my
work again and that's something that we know a lot of enterprise...of particularly been asking for.
Once I do login though what's really been the point of the exercise.
So,...see that it's.
Logged in with my work account.
...to pop open the account manager page here just to give you a
few pointers.
You'll see that I've signed into what's known as my personalization account and that
kinda gives you the first clue as to what we've been using this thing...
those of you been using it before probably found that...a certain number of settings
...in visual studio so that when you sign in on multiple boxes you don't have to go ahead and do
all that tedious work...how you like the edit to sets up which windows you like
open etc that's a real pain and we recognize that people don't enjoy it and enjoy that a
...that since two thousand thirteen has been a feature we broaden the number of things that
were actually writing now but much more interesting now is that we've also provided if you look at
this area here a set of other accounts and you'll see another one is just appeared in as the
writing settings came online?
And, that is actually a...
microsoft account that I'm also using the nice thing about visual studio twenty
fifteen if we provide the ability vu to connect up to your personalization account here
in the account manager as many as
you want accounts that you use for other things so let's say for instance that you have a
live account associated with your msdn subscription or live account
...using in a particular project for connecting to measure services
at any of those...can be chained up so you only have...once and that's the big deal
here that's the goal so that we provide a single sign
in experience visual studio that manages all of the kinds of a camps that you care about with respect to
the development activities and we'll see how that plays out we take a look over here
and server explorer.
Occasionallywhen you first sign in you will find that?
You have to sign in.
...each account and that's fine and the reason for that is because we don't
want to be a caching your credentials when you log out we...leave those lying around on the
machines so since I just signed in I should never see that dialogue but I just
...once as long as I stay signed into visual studio all of the camps that
...signed into will remain in place so you can see that can see all of my
...subscriptions and that means.
That when I cracking open for instance this web apps node will actually go ahead and find
the test databases actually this one is actually attached to my msdn subscription that
access through that live...that the microsoft account so I can have as many of those
accounts as I...to access as many services as I wish to access and, we hope that you'll find that
to...useful feature.
Another feature that we've added which I think you'll find hopefully useful in terms
of being personalize...to the way you use the world how many
of you systematically ignore notifications in visual studio?
Yeah, I figure as much.
And, the reason for that I we recognize that there's been a certain amount of
...noise and lack of...in the notifications experience
is...didn't necessarily see things that you ted about ok well in twenty fifty in the
world is changing what you're seeing here don't worry the world hasn't suddenly moved forward to the middle
of next year or whatever that might happen visual studio twenty fifteen update one is not
...hissed but we're seeing here is what the new notifications experience looks like
I'm just put some sample items into the notification hub here for
you to say you see a couple of things here.
Firstly we've introduced some categorization you can see that...a category
...product updates and the category
here that's a tentative one with thinking about around troubleshooting...what another
benefits of signing in by the way is that when you sign in it gives us the opportunity when you send
a smil which is this little guy up here if you haven't used them to send feedback to actually get in
touch with you and close the loop about some problems that you might be saying anyway that's
...side we now have categories in the notifications
And,...that should hopefully help you to find the things that you care about
...this guy...the top is what we call a promoted notification
and those are really for things that we think everybody needs to know and, that are incredibly
high importance so obviously we think are updates are really important but the kinds of things you
also see up there is if you're licenses about to
expire you would see that and you also see the read notification like up in the
tallwhen that happens one final piece of personalization is the always ignore
button...so if you've decided that and,
I really don't think you should decide this but...sake of argument
...say that you just aren't interested in application...I think that would be a mistake but
you'll call I can say I want to see updates like that in the future I can always signal
...it's actually got a little bit are you sure here but it's now...always ignored state and assumes
I quit the notifications with...on legacy updates of that...again so what
...allows you to do is team down your experience so you just see stuff that you care about and hopefully
we'll find a because we take telemetry on this kind of thing well,
actually find out what it is you guys really care about...so it'll help us tonightwhat's going on?
So, that's notifications just one of what quickly.
The...here you see that it dates works with your work or
school accounts and not only do we...your settings but we also...connected services.
we've reduced the cluster and hopefully we've allowed you to see any what you care about another way that
we're working to make sure that we work with all of the or devices and a personalize to the device world
that you're living in is that we've added we've been working since visual
studio twenty thirteen to improve our high dpi support now I see a number of
you a packing surface threes or some and a lot of
high dpi devices on the market today more people working on them and we know that we want to
provide first-class experience that we did a bunch of work in twenty thirteen
to get ourselves better in that world and one of the things that you'll probably notice if
you're running on a high dpi device with twenty fifteen is that we've
...really upped the ante on icons and I hope you can see that the
...the toolbar the top is not-so-nice as the one at the bottom that there
are some nice improvements in clarity...christmas on those icons that
high dpi and that's something you'll see throughout the product because this is actually a service that we have
within visual studio...allows everyone who works inside the visual studio environment to
pick-up icons high dpi nice crisp icons you should see that
improvement spreading throughout the product another way that we're taking into account.
Your particular device preferences is better shown in a
I personally have a laptop here that I work on all the time when I'm out
in aboutmaybe I'm at home and that's what that's my typical environment for a lot
of time but I also work have a multimodal sets up now I'm sure that's not on typical
right a lot of you guys probably working a multimodal setups as well one of the things that's a real royal
...when I'm working with visual studio is to have to keep rearranging all of my
tool windows said that they work with the particular environment that I'm working on so we've
got a nice new feature here which allows you to deal with exactly that scenario
...see here on the window menu we have a new feature that allows you just save a window layout
okay and that would allow me for instance if I chose save when...here I could make
...named...and that would store away all of the layouts of all the tool windows
...part of visual studio now rather than create
...new one here actually made a couple already because the flip side of that is you
can also apply them dynamically say let's suppose that I'm back at my big
multimodal setup I can just say control to and
...this up and you can see now actually doesn't look great on this screen and that's not surprising because
it's currently running...laptop but just to illustrate that picked up all of my to windows that and I can have
as many of those named lapses I one I can go nuts on that if I have different ways of working in
...perhaps when I'm working in a designer I use a certain set of to windows when I'm working
...I've got my debugging view...my sequel type view all you
name it if you've got different tool windows that you like to have up and you want to switch quickly and easily
between those super easy to do that now so I'm actually going to go ahead and the switch back.
My laptop environment and you can see that as easy as the
hit a button very straightforward to use the nice thing is those are actually roamed although the
setting of course is not think about it for a while you...about...
You have be a bad idea if we if we...the setting itself but we do
...the there's different lapse that you choose to create a as long as you are signed into
...studio so you create as many as you like party on hope you
enjoy them now here's one that requires me to use my hands
okay we have just enabled in twenty fifty
in touch in the visual studio...ok, so, I can pinched resume.
...to select.
I can select a row by tapping here in the margin.
...that selects the whole row.
I can of course.
...and hold which.
Was always enabled the thing...how does that...now into a menu that isn't quite
...touch friendly so we recognize that we've
stretch the envelope to a certain degree the scenario that we had in mind here
is that we think it's really important for scenarios where your say on a plane or train and
...using a touch machine and you want to do some reading and scrolling and moving around
inside of your code we think it's really important that we enable that first however we do think that
...going forward is probably going to be more than that and the id so we'd be interested to hear from you guys
about what you think is most important the next if you if you care about the touch scenario my
email address and my twitter handler on the front of this slide so please do go ahead and send me
...on that we'd love to hear about what you think comes next in
the touch world but sure, enough it works...we have you like that?
So, that...the...of today's discussion what I really want to show
you here is how we've done some work in visual studio to improve?
The find fix cycle as we call it so,
how we how we work with finding and fixing issues in your code I'm going
to actually take a short detour through a few other little bits and pieces in the editor but,
we will get to finding and fixing stuff fairly quickly so please when I switch
back then obsess about the reads google you'll be saying?
We're going to obsess about it now there's a reads we go right there it is
...you can't help yourself any.
Anyhow so first I would like to say that one of the tenets that
we've always had releases visual studio two thousand twelve is that we...you to
...code and work in your code without having to go off into
separate tool windows anddistract yourself with other things so how many of you guys...ever use...
About half again because one of my favorite...features for this reason
said here I've gota method that I'm going to take a quick look at now imagine I'm working on a
brand-new paid base here I'm just trying to understand how...constructed and,
typically in pretty pretty peak days what you would have done is perhaps you...done...twelve
...definition...been hitting up...twelve chain and
...been a giant what of windows
...the between you and your final destination while with...
We can simply go.
...twelve.
He says...some confidence.
Definition.
We'll get a...straight into the method
okay and the nice thing about paint the really nice thing is it doesn't stop there so
for instance if I'm if I decide I'm interested in this event handler I can peak again.
And,...starts...a nice little breadcrumbs riled up at the top here and those by the way if you
have discover them there's a keyboard shortcut for backing enforcing through those and,
that's control control.
Alt and minus to go back and control plus to go forward so there's a couple
you really useful shortcuts if you're working with...I know lots of folks...work with the
edits...really want to keep their hands-off the mouse and say we're pretty keno keyboard shortcuts which is why I'm kind of
disappointed all...twelve this playing up on this machine at this point.
Nevertheless say web...is a great experience for keeping you in context so you can always see
way you started your journey through the code and you can always track back and
forth without ever losing that context and that principle is one that we think is very useful
and lots of other places too so we've taken the idea and run with it and a couple other places.
And, I'm just going to show you some of those now.
So, this is a xhtml project I'm going to crockett and...here.
...going to select one of these buttons and you'll notice that I have some
styles associated with those buttons here now wouldn't it be neat if.
You know, what's coming...
Wouldn't it be neat if you could pick...definition for styles to?
Furthermore wouldn't it be neat if you could just live it...those and see the results on the design
and I think that's pretty nice so,...definition works.
Right here in this animal designer which is great normal getting lost in
endless chains of dictionaries this should make life a whole lot easier, for example, develop we had.
Next thing that we've done with...just go ahead here and
set a bright point on this line you may have seen this in some of the earlier demos but if you have
noticed it let's suppose now that I want to set some conditional
break points.
We've now invented something that you might call...dialogue ok so if you
...the debug settings...before you'll probably
have notice that it comes up in a and a dialogue box that probably obscures the code that you're working on
the nice thing about a...is that it sits inline...and into linear thing it's between
your lines of code and it never ever obscures the code that you
were looking at when you invoked so
same benefits apply here what this means is now if I'm wanting to set some conditions here
I can tell that I'm actually in the context of something that's going to have these variables so I can actually
start typing meaningful conditionals here that actually refer to the code that I'm working
and without actually losing the code that I need to refer to we think that's important so that's another use of
...the you'll see...twenty fifteen and we...you like that one too.
Another place where we work hard to ensure
that we don't lose your context whilst you're looking at your code.
In giving you understanding of...code via code
...okay so you probably many
of noticed if you've not seen it beforecode lenses up here.
Above in a...csharp file its
here above the method heading and you can see that I can actually look at things like changes references
insightful when I...guide and once again this is
the supported by a keyboard shortcut which is alt and then the number of the lens that you're using...the
code lenses and extensible mechanism you can see now that I've got my changes and
there obviously this is a demo project on the demo getrepo so they're not
terribly interesting changes but you could imagine real-world project that...be seeing the changes
from your team so you can get that context on what's happening in your projects and there's also a
...for looking at unit test...coverage and that kind of thing
...the reference one which is probably the one that a lot of people use the most which allows you to dive
off the references to methods so forth but all of those...you as a uniform set to
keep your focus on the code whilst actually understanding more about the
code so you never have believed in order to find out more that's...
that well that's the twenty thirteen fiji probably saying and...you showed me this...twenty fifteen
to well the world has changed and if you looked carefully at that style dictionary
...file you might have...that down at the bottom there's a new kind of lenz okay.
And, I'll show it magnified here for a moment then I'll actually go
and actuator and you can see here that what showing me is some of that
file level information from gate that was present in the code...stuff
...and vb files so this is available now if it's not the csharp of eb files that
doesn't have traditional code...the...
is available for things like ...history so forth and more stuff that's that
sort of file scope will probably be coming to the file baselines here this is good news for
cplus-plus...html javascript all of those other places where you don't have code
...today so you can get that contextual information without ever having to leave you
code file...that's going to help.
Now the moment you been waiting for I'm going to get back to the read squiggles.
So,...clearly this project has some errors in it and that's not
...state for me you may be
...than I am sure...it's pretty common to have errors and issues in your code and,
what we've tried to do in visual studio twenty fifteen
...and experience that...both find and fix those issues more easily
than you could before so let's take a look at what that looks like?
Firstly you'll notice here in the error list that there
are a few a small changes that ...you may have noticed...you'll see that we
now have a link here in the code column more on the moment but
you also find that when we double-click on item here.
I'm going to just quickly zoom in you'll see that are
lightbulb has appeared on the line that I navigated to say where the light bulb is a new
two thousand fifteen feature if you use the roslyn preview
bits before you may have seen it...earlier iteration there this is now
platform feature that is available across all languages not just the one supported by the...compiler.
Light bulbs are a new way of exposing
fixes and quick actions that we can take on...
ok so let's go and that guy what does he show is.
Little bit of a tour of the anatomy here first you'll see that
on the left here I'm seeing a whole list of things that I could do to fix
the problem that I was experiencing so, there are various different options and as I
move down through them in a moment you'll see that the preview which is over on the right-hand
side actually shows me what I'm going to get when I take that
action so you'll see here in this case I'm getting a green-line for
...paint dot...which is going to be added to the top of
my the code and I can have complete confidence...what that action is going to
...particular single file cases and in many cases fixes are single file so you can pretty
much take them based only on what you're seeing in that preview we think that useful.
So, what control...which is actually the for some reason
my keyboards not playing ball control dot
visual friend it's the control period it's actually they should keyboard shortcuts and you'll see
that's when we hover over the...to tells us about
that allows us very quickly to move through items
from the keyboard so I can from the airlift I just go
...to move through my...for instance as I move on to a new...
I will actually find myself.
To immediately take the action I'm going to use the massive...some reason like he was
playing up control dot would get me straight to here...I can reeve around within the.
...to choose the action that I want.
And, then quickly take it just by hitting enter ok so imagine
if an in most cases we hope this is true the communist action will be at the top
of the list so to fakes all I need to do is
...eight in the error list control dot to bring up the
light bulb and, my problem.
Is fixed ok so that's a real quick workflow
...controlled up...all if it's not the first choice
...control dot move up and down with the arrow keys select the
...you want it enter so we really tried to think about the keyboard interaction
here because we know that most denies work hands-off the mouse a lot of the time so we want
to make sure that works but as you've seen also it works great with the with the mouse as well?
That's my first issues solved.
I'm now going to roll down.
And, as I roll down I notice because I've got pretty good eyes that this.
Color here has got a slightly different colorized
...than the similar-type comes elsewhere in the code now this
is not as aggressive as a reads google so hopefully didn't draw your eyes straight away
bob as...working you might notice things like this coming out and this is
...a thing of class suggestion ok so basically if you're seeing one of these
...to...you about this because it's not going to prevent you from compiling your code but what is
trying to tell you is there's a there's a thing that could improve here if you if you want to take a look
...and to try fixing...try that and it's the same lightbulb you can see it's telling is that the
...redundant which you probably spotted already and,
here we're seeing that very same experience.
Okay, what we have is the remove unnecessary gauss which is the only option we have available to
...you can see the preview...telling is exactly what we're going to get in this single file
in this case it's kind of interesting tonight that we've also got the option?
Of taking the action at a different scope okay so we can take that action
and this also works with the keyboard I can arrow key my way down into here and have around so,
that works just great I can choose to take that action at the whole
solutions scope in fact that's actually what I'm going to do?
...solution and we get the preview changes dialogue which you've probably seen before which deals with
the multi file case and allows us to see exactly what changes are being made.
Where the code and that would basically fix-all the redundant costs...present in my
...instead of just the one so I can apply that and everything's done?
So, you can see that we're dealing now with two classes of thing...the error class of thing
we'll show you ...lightbulb hovering over the square root
of all in cases where it's not so important that we convey information
to aggressively we have a
more subtle treatment but still by hovering all by moving onto that line and hitting controlled all you'll see the
lightbulb up here so keyboard mouse works just great
...suggestions or...errors for dealing with those the nice thing about these like
...by the way in passing and I should mention this because I think some of the probably be
...leads and the folksy build libraries and the audience is
that the lightbulb mechanisms used by the roslyn compiler to
expose and extensibility point and the key extensibility point that exposes called
analyses, analyses are really cool new a feature in
the roslyn compiler system and what they allow you to do is to package up
the sets of rules about things that might go wrong in your library or
...coding mistakes...patterns if you like so what that means is a library author or as a
dev lead...common problems in approach a particular project, you know,
people are always making this code mistake what you can do is package up a way of detecting
values issues having them showing up by the id and allowing your developers
not only to find them but also to fix them because you can also package up the fix so the
...a light a package
...as well so if you're working with manage languages visual bit visual basic and,
csharp ...the analyze a framework something I really recommend you take a look at and
that's another talk you'll see in my references section which is by
dustin campbell and he'll give you walk through how to build one of those it really not that hard to
construct and analyzer the whole lightbulb framework is
in fact extensible and is used by a number of other languages too so it's not just
manage languages as I say that have the light bulbs but rather than of probably taken the
furthest manage languages a experience is probably the most advanced at this point?
So, what I'm going to do now?
Run some code analysis.
Now while I'm doing that I...honesty poll...
How many of you have ever done this?
You've.
Worked pretty hard and getting the functionality of your project
up and running everything's great and you get to
...a probably a few weeks out from...and somebody thinks it would be a great idea to run code analysis on the solution.
...and, what happens there's a whole bunch of bugs get raised right they're all in the system and,
what actually then happens is the systematically...because they're not stopping anything from shipping
...I don't know if you've ever seen that happen before...you know,
I think it's not that uncommon...
Running code analysis in a static way has some hazards in
...regard I mentioned
analyses earlier on the other key and key advantage of
...is that they run and I'm going to show you this rightnow by...that.
Redundant cast you see that the light bulb paid immediately as soon as I
typed analyses run alive then requirements and batch things up
...then require me to run code analysis in a batch way
now we're moving a lot of things out of the static analysis world into the
...world as you might expect to take advantage of this feature because this means that as
you're typing you get the information you need...not only that you get the...which is pretty cool
but, there's still going to be a ton of things that are still living in
analyzes.
That run statically so in the static analysis world and.
Analysis again.
The static analysis world has changed in visual studio twenty fifteen
to so you might notice that all my code analysis results here
...showing up in the error list why is that okay we like to think of the
error list now as being kind of...one-stop-shop for everything that might
be wrong all need tweaking or touching in your code we don't have to have you
...to two separate places in order to figure things out and the
pasta code analysis window was this separate thing that ran over here it was kind of not
integrative and that didn't really make a ton of sense particularly in the light of the fact that a
lot of analysis is now going to be done life anyway and that's the trend
in analysis so we thought it would be much better if you actually had a way to see
all of the things that might be or to do list if you like for the code located in one spot and
that's the error list map you might be saying well heck now I've got all this junk in my error list item one
that while we thought about that too and the other thing that we've done in the
airlift here...actually a whole bunch of things that we've done in the errors but the thing that I think
you'll find useful is we've actually enabled I'm just going to
...column here.
The ability to dynamically filter your error list so that you can actually
...on the thing that you care about most.
So, in this case for instance let's suppose...somebody had done that big static analysis run
and we've got a bunch of bugs and I decided that actually what I really want to do is focusing on the naming
bugs you can see we've implemented xcel style filtering here so if
...used xcel tables you've seen that they have this notion of being able to
the filter each column based on its contents so we've done the same thing...the same
paradigm and what we can see here is that we have a certain number of naming issues?
And, I'm going to focus in on those first.
And, I'm kinda interested in this first one which is that I've got
...utilize name space and the tool is saying well you really shouldn't use utilitze
and abbreviation how do I know that by the way while I can hit my
cuddling here?
Okay.
...of the universal features that we...in the error
...now is you can be able to get a link to the error
in question as much as we can find it right from within the...and you can hit that up by the by clicking the
...fone and...when you're selecting an error in the
airlift now they're going to be cases where you don't actually have a direct matched for instance if you
using someone else's library that actually doesn't have static documentation built for it
yet and those cases we know that often times you're going to be picking up the internet you
...going...a bing search for that or a search with other search...
...going to be searching you probably going to have to strip out a bunch of stuff you usual workflow
might be copy and paste from the airlift pop into some search box and it return and,
you get some search results and that'll be great and it might help you solve your...what we've actually done
now in twenty fifteen is we you'll notice that we send searches
straight debate we actually formulate that search...for you.
And, we're working with the being team to actually make that search ever
more appropriate to the code that you're working on so we actually send a little bit
of context across that as well like the kind of project that you're working on so
that we can get better search results so, you should find that even when it's not and like it is in this
case getting a piece of static content that we have...documentation it you should
get pretty decent help to help you fix those errors that you
see anyway all that side...identify should be spelled correctly and
the utilizes some kind of abbreviations I shouldn't be doing that.
Just put...definition of my...here and I'm going to show you one extra
super-power for the lightbulb ok so, light bulbs I
mentioned a great for fixing things you've already seen that...what I'm going to do here is I'm actually going
to start to try and fix this up so I
should really be calling this utilities now you'll...
...column I should really.
...as something very...about my keyboard by the moment I'm going to carry on
in this case you can see that what's happened is there's a dotted line around my.
Token that I'm typing and what that means is that it started suggesting that I might
want to be in a rename refractive session okay because it recognize that utilities obviously being
a namespaces going to be listed all over my code and what I really want to
do is have a rename refractive session and the place where that lives now is on the
lightbulb okay so you get that situation you're typing you
...control dot you see the light bulb you initiate a rename session?
And, in that case I just took it with...preview and, it's actually...ahead and on-the-job.
So, rename re factor which is an on-demand action you can see there is now being
shown also through the light...and that means we've been able to...clots are the
...context menu in the editor a little bit because...a whole bunch about class-action that were
was sitting on...so hopefully it'll be a we be easy as a posit list now you'll see if you do have
it right click that we remind you that everything's on quick actions now by putting the lightbulb...the top so,
if you take one thing away from here today if you're
user of this kind of code fixing thing control dot is your new best friend okay, so,
try it see what you think.
One final piece that I want to touch on.
Control comma...navigate to.
Another methods that is here my code and here you'll see that this is another instance
of some of the changes that we made in visual studio twenty thirteen things
like navigate to work in these inline windows now rather than being in a tool
...so you don't actually have to lose the context of your...navigating around so control common
that gets me into navigate...can quickly move around you see it's actually bring up
a for a provisional wvu on each of these methods as I go so there I had one that was in the
...cs not particular interesting but you'll notice it's appeared in a provisional tab up on the top right
that that's not a real tablet wednesday open when I navigate ...going to go away but making
hovering prototype is the method I want to work on today I'm going to take a quick look.
And, I notice that I have some code here but I think could use a little bit of refactoring and
...to extract method here same thing applies ok so
...once again of selected some code and I can control dot
or just this and I can use extract method and you can see we're getting all of the
eyes preview...selling...exactly what's going to happen when we extract method I can go ahead and
extract and I'm immediately into a rename session which allows me to
...not only the new method that I've extracted but also the instantiation of it so,
I'm going to say ...
...andthat session is complete ok so that's just a
nice new feature that the manage languages folks have come up with the
wghooks nicely into the light bulb so lightbulb...very much active in
the manage languages well but you also find some of them and cplus-plus.
There are some great examples there so for instance if you're working in a
...today in cplus-plus you start defining signature of a method and you want to go
do the implementation there's a light bulb...you do that as well so,
...you working across to files in fact that...actually leverages...that's pretty cool.
And, ...you type in that method as you go.
Talking of cplus-plus.
If your code analysis guy and you cplus-plus recognize I'm talking to a relatively small
crammed here but, the if you're using code analysis
...cplus-plus you might think well gosh how on earth they
...all of that lovely detailed I used to...my code analysis window into that tiny six
line box the bottom of the screen and the answer is we are not we're not because we've actually put it
in a better place a place that is hopefully much more useful
to you so you'll notice here in my error list if I just zoom in a little bit as a new little
icon there that looks like an arrow pointing out of a
boxes a promotion type of thing and if I hit not guy when I've done some
kind analysis as I have on this project for cases where there is dens content that relates to
...code we put them now into this editor hosted environment and what
that means it's right next to the code that relates to ok
...oftentimes with these things you're wanting to refer back and forth in this case
...a formal proof of why I'm using on initialized memory in this case and actually steps me through it but, these and
these analysis situations...quite typically like this way you have a detailed explanation of something
you might need a little time to work through that so not only can you work at
...through it right next to the k that refers to you can also if you want to keep hanging around
for a while pop it out to a tool winded and pocket somewhere so that
you can work on that thing for an extended period and move it to a location that
you might you might prefer so well that shows you there is that you know,
...one-stop-shop for all things analysis and
...is the airlift it works across multiple languages in many cases we provide you
with fixes that will help you to fix the issues your finding and
we're also providing you with the cabling to provide you it's more information about the areas the hissing we
...that will that already help you as you go about fixing errors?
So, I already mentioned that this is an extensible thing you can write your own
lightbulb should you choose to do so if you're interested in that please do come and see me on the visual cs and
...me align ...relatively straightforward thing to construct if
you're manage languages person by fob easiest way to address them is to
use the analyzes framework that I referred to earlier.
Another point that.
Other people realize about the editor but not everyone has seen.
Is that the editor itself is highly
extensible and what we found is that we've got an awful lot of folks constructing?
All kinds of extensions to visual studio that address the edits
...famously good examples of that would be re sharp which I'm sure a lot of you
if you manage languages uses...already using
...plenty of other examples out that I'm one that comes from our own
internal world is ...created by the bing team
at any of you come across being developed persistent a few a few hands out there I think
after this you might want to go and take a look at it what I'm going to do here is just as a final
thing show you the feature?
That that's not what I wanted to...
And, after going up this way.
The big guys...constructing a great feature that allows you to search
...samples but you can...that thing from pretty much anywhere so here
let's say I want to work to create a new save method from my
...utility that I've been constructing and I want to say vpf
converse.
Has jpeg?
...that thing up.
And, what we'll do hereand,
in fact if you if I'd been able to use control alt fone it would have come up
in a nice window inside the editor it can take me to code snippets from
all over the internet allow me to quickly capture them and place them into my
caves this will help the typical places like stack overflowed also books for relevant projects
on gab samples so forth and,
...me to select a piece of code that I want to use copy it and paste
...into my code to start using it
and that search is very much aware of the project type that I'm working in
...samples that are actually relevant to the thing I'm working on rather than just doing a plain old
...search on a on a simple search engines say that's a way in which the
...of added valueto the editor experience by providing you with that kind of
contextual thing that gives you a way of staying inside the edits and now I now I didn't show inside there
is a trust me if the keyboard...this thing I've been working correctly control fone?
Would have got me to a beautiful little window that sits inside the editor that's me exactly the same
...just so we do in a to window that ...document windows so, I encourage you to check out all the
...extensions that are on the on the extensions gallery through the extensions manager and,
see what they can do to add value to you'll ...editing experience...of course now
that community addition exists you can do all of that for free?
I mention code...earlier on and one of the pieces of feedback that we
heard repeatedly from customers was that...you really wish that thing wasn't
justin ultimate good nears it's not anymore we had...it's going to be
...two thousand fifteen going forward so you know, be able to use guidelines.
So,...coming to the end now and I just want
to encourage you to use one of the many channels of sharing feedback
visual studio we have lots of channels but one of them I really want to highlight is send
ismail as anyone center...yeah, quite a few a frowned.
Fu I'm financial I read all of the...the franz and,
smiles that have anything to do with the editor is one of the things that I spend a lot of time on we
do take that feedback extremely seriously and you know,
bugs get...things get changed as a result of it as a please do you send a
small it it's really getting richer and richer every time we update
its capabilities include the ability to grab screen grabs so forth it's also getting...doing
things like grabbing dumps in the cases of crash scenarios other issues like that so,
...where enhancing that feature more and more with every update to make sure that we have a great channel
to make sure we understand what's going on with you...with your feedback there's also use
...voice which as you...with the last slide has been successfully used to persuade us to do things that
...matter to you guys so that's a great place for suggestions it's good because it lets you
vote things up and down so you can use the community to leverage of feedback in that case the one we did
...three-and-a-half thousand votes we knew it was the trending for folks and we took some notice about
user voices a great place connect is another great place to raise things...more of the class
of bugs that gives you a more of a back and forth channel with us so that you can actually
hear feedback about what's happening with your bug although what's this space with send
...we're hoping to make that a little bit more back and forth to?
So, now you've seen this talk ...whole bunch of things I really want to recommend that you do with some of the rest...time
...and I'm going to stop very shortly...there's a few minutes for questions the
analyzes I've already banged on about so one bang on about them anymore but please
...suggestions talk on that is also got a great talk on the csharp and
vb enhancements if you're a manage languages person go see that I'll tell you everything you need to
know not only about the new id features like the rename refactoring so forth but also
about language features that they've been working on and csharp six...fourteen there's also
a great session on extensions please do go get the ossie give us feedback
...and do try our friends of beings being developed persistent it's a great...feature
...extension let them know what you think there's a nice link
...the let you get now I want to go to questions?
So, please do come to the microphones if you have a question and,
speak clearly and slowly so that everyone can...
Please do take the michael.
Go ahead on the left there by an israeli mechanism whereby I can selected
block of code and when I copy it all of the references become fully qualified...when I
...all only the ones that I don't have using
...scores remain fully qualified that's a really awesome feature I love the
idea I'd I'm not aware of one right now it sounds like the kind of thing that might be
...extension capability that we could perhapsone of
...extensions work on but I'm not aware of one that does that say if I'm understanding
incorrectly...basically haven't strip out fully qualified stuff or added when it
goes to a target that requires the full qualification up yet we
don't I don't think we have anything that does that right now but that sounds really nice idea...
Doing.
...just...unlawful for this...this up one of the things with visual studio...
things tremendous id probably I've been developing for fifteen years and
I find it's very solid...when it comes to doing things such as like mark-up
and more like less not like dot net for server-side stuff I some
feel it's almost like not over killed but it doesn't feel as lean online as I want to funders doing
markup like client-side styling...is there anythingthat
you guys would be looking at to make it a little more of a choice and maybe using something like sublime
orone of the things that hopefully...in the keynote this morning was one option that's coming around
there is the new visual studio code environment which provides a super lightweight environment and
I know the recessions here a build about that but,
we're also interested to think about whether there's actually something that we could do inside visual studio in the future
...I'm interested say that piece of feedback I think there are lots of
...like the really super lightweight environment and just to ask a question back
in return and I'd love to...the where I'm going to be on the visual studio stand in the
...platform tools area later so-if you want-to put by that'd be great
but, what seven yet I think we may have scope for a
lightweight environment even within the visual studio area to in possible features
I'm wondering whether your goal there is this the style of editing
where you're literally just sitting up files almost using file association and...popping a file open
in the editor of you really don't care very much maybe even about solutions and projects particularly in
the worldmany things don't even have them ...and you're much more interested in just...opening editor
...and community does look good I haven't played with the yet so maybe that would be a solution
but if you are doing a lot of...would be nice to suh maybe toggle
so now I'm hearing another story which is kind of the idea that
...just too many features and you just want to see the ones that relate to the thing that you're working on is
...a miami...yeah,
okay, that's also something we've been talking about so that's good feedback we don't have anything right now it
looks like we now have something at both ends of the spectrum a super lightweight
...visual studio code and then the full id and...
In the main product and even on...like a set of with the id when you initial
...doing more web cpr yep ...an option to say
...mode and that is your lightweight word is yes the heavier,
yeah, I like the idea I think it's something we definitely need to discuss the future releases
...thanks and this looks this...so thank you thank you appreciate it.
Hi, I'm assuming that a lot of the features for like the code...whatnot
required do like if you have multiple projects to have like a project reference between them to be able
to directly navigate...code and but a lot of times, you know,
when you want to have things or module you set up multiple solutions
...you do assembly references in between them?
And, I would assume that this code people
...work with assembly references right well that's actually
a question that's ...for the compiler guys but I think that's definitely a scenario that
...off and one that they've been working on making...because really familial
...video-only answers one hand I mean you own both multiple pieces
...for...purposes you have to...reference absolutely and I'm pretty certain that's one that they've
...my word for it...great feta...a dusters...
there in this is dustin session would be a great place to go to...that question okay, but,
they're also understands as well so but, yeah,
that's absolutely scenario that they care...okay thank you bye.
...thank you time and have a great build?